In this lesson, you will learn how to use Wipe and Replace feature.
It's been sort of a yeah, a poverty version of finding the replace features that every
detour has, but this feature allows you to transform your code intelligently across the
whole project.
So let's talk a bit how it works and what it is.
Wipe and Replace features start just like normal finding the replace feature, but instead
of doing the simple replacement when sort of applies any IPROM to each match.
That means that every replacement is context aware.
It looks at how the code is used and adapts the transformation to feel that specific
place.
So it's really smart.
You can use it to massive the factors that touch hundreds of files of the whole
project.
For example, you can rename variable semantically generate the commentation or remove
feature flags all in one single intelligent operation.
It's really a big forward step from basic search and replace and it was built for developers
who was really do replacement smarter, safer with automation across the whole code base.
So now it's time to see how it works.
I will switch to be surfed up and I will open past for a strange shaker file and we need
to find something we want to replace, but something challenging for just a simple replace
operation.
So imagine we have a feedback, we want to rename this feedback to recommendation.
Because this feedback variable is used really to open in our file, it uses the suggest
variable in our methods, we are doing it as a prop.
As a result, we also use this one in comments, we also use this here and another object
is the final object and we use it also right here when we have off feedback array.
And yes, we use it here so a lot of places where we use feedback and we want to rename
it to recommendation.
So imagine we don't have a webinar place and I will show you how we will do it with
manual find another place feature.
I will just mention feedback, but because we have off feedback, I need to choose the
much case to exclude this off feedback from the changes because it starts from capital
letter and I cannot do it both at the same time.
And I also will use my the whole word of all the safety because if you have a word like
I don't know feedback is a part of another word or for example we have some prefix before
after so it will also be replaced so I want to be safer and I will now enter word word
I want, recommendation.
And just click replace all the places right here you can see the history of what words
will be replaced.
Okay, you see it was replaced, now we need to replace off feedback, off feedback to over
recommendation.
I still will be use the much case and the much whole word restrictions and I will replace
it.
So as you see we need to write a text, we need to do it in two operations, we also not
really sure if we didn't do the replacements, we don't want, so.
And now let me show you how work is a normal find a wide end of the place, so we mentioned
what work we want to replace feedback.
And now in the place work we just enable the vibe under the place mode and we can enter
a problem.
So I would say replace feedback was a word, doesn't matter to start from capital letter
or small letter, replace it to recommendation in the whole project.
And in the foundation in the whole project and I will click run, we see it started the
new chart with a prompt and let's see how it was replaced.
Oh, we see it replace the variables right here, it replace the process variable when we add
a new item to array as a result, when we were doing something, we also update the comments
of the comments, fine, we also updated the comments here, but yeah, I was interested if it
will replace, so we see we have all feedback and it was replaced all recommendation.
And everywhere.
So it's really smart and you can save your time, we of course accept all the changes.
Now we want to show you one more feature of this web under place, you can use two modes to
the smart mode and the fast mode.
The smart mode is uses more advanced server models that applies each change really carefully,
it can be perfect when accuracy matters, like when you refactor, watch project or generating
some important documentation and you really want it to be able to place everything carefully
and smart.
And we use the smart replacement here because we have variables in different edges to it.
For example, the fast mode, you can use, you just want to do some quick updates across
many files and don't really need some deep reasoning behind every change, because this is
lighter, weaker and applies changes right away.
And the switch between modes, you can use this arrow and just switch.
If you, you know, if you do something difficult, just use a smart mode or just on camera
and use smart mode always.
So, in this lesson, we learned how the web under place feature works.
I hope you will use it now more often because this tool helps refactor hundreds of lines
of code, much easier with AI help and now we can choose between smart and fast modes, so
you also know how it works.
Okay, and see you in the next lesson.